Bo Li, PhD student in ML

A Linde Allé, 2850 Nærum, Denmark

+45 60 69 82 98 Website

blia@dtu.dk



in Bo Li



Summary

(7) lvn1874

A self-motivated, organised and dedicated Ph.D. with proven mathematical skills and a desire to learn more. 7+ years of experience using machine learning and deep learning for analysing various data types (medical images, spectra, and surveillance videos). Reliable team player and skilled at analytical thinking and creative problem-solving. Super fascinated by coding.

Research:

Machine/Deep Learning

Optimization

Federated learning

Uncertainty estimation

Anomaly detection PyTorch & Python Computer vision

Scholar

Spectroscopy analysis

Education

2021 - Now PhD, Technical University of Denmark Applied Mathematics and Computer Science Topic: Federated Machine Learning for Raman spectra and Surface-Enhanced Raman spectra

(SERS)

■ Visiting PhD student, CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security 2022 - 2023

Topic: Accelerating the convergence of federated learning algorithms under high data hetero-

geneity

M.Sc., Technical University of Denmark Mathematical Modelling and Computation 2016 - 2018

Thesis: Active multitask learning for object recognition in images using deep neural networks

B.Sc., Jilin University Financial Engineering. 2012 - 2016

Thesis: The analysis of monetary factor in the context of capital market

Work Experience

Researcher Ghent University - Imec, Supervisor: Dr. Sam Leroux, Prof. Pieter Simones 2019 - 2021

Develop deep neural networks for detecting anomalies in surveillance videos under adverse

weather • Develop distillation-learning based hardware-efficient framework for traffic counting

2018 - 2018 **Research Assistant** Technical University of Denmark, Supervisor: *Prof. Tommy Alstrom*

• Explore uncertainty calibration within active learning for medical image segmentation

• Develop region-based acquisition strategy to reduce labelling effort

Teaching Assistant Technical University of Denmark 2018 - 2022

• Deep learning, 2021, 2023 • Bayesian machine learning, 2022 • Advanced data analysis, 2018

Publications

B. Li, Y. Esfandiari, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, and S. U. Stich, Synthetic data shuffling accelerates the convergence of federated learning under data heterogeneity, 2023, arXiv: 2306.13263 [cs.LG].

B. Li, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, and S. U. Stich, "On the effectiveness of partial variance reduction in federated learning with heterogeneous data," in Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), Jun. 2023, pp. 3964–3973.

B. Li, G. Zappalá, E. Dumont, et al., "Nitroaromatic explosives' detection and quantification using an attention-based transformer on surface-enhanced raman spectroscopy maps," Analyst, 2023. 🔗 URL: http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/D3AN00446E.

- **B. Li***, X. Jiang*, M. N. Schmidt, T. S. Alstrøm, and S. U. Stich, An improved analysis of per-sample and per-update clipping in federated learning, 2023.
- **B. Li**, M. N. Schmidt, and T. S. Alstrøm, "Raman spectrum matching with contrastive representation learning," *Analyst*, 2022. ODI: 10.1039/D2AN00403H.
- **B. Li***, S. Leroux*, and P. Simoens, "Automated training of location-specific edge models for traffic counting," *Computers Electrical Engineering*, vol. 99, p. 107 763, 2022, ISSN: 0045-7906.
- **B. Li***, S. Leroux*, and P. Simoens, "Multi-branch neural networks for video anomaly detection in adverse lighting and weather conditions," in *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)*, Jan. 2022, pp. 2358–2366.
- **B. Li**, S. Leroux, and P. Simoens, "Decoupled appearance and motion learning for efficient anomaly detection in surveillance video," *Computer Vision and Image Understanding*, vol. 210, p. 103 249, 2021, ISSN: 1077-3142.
- **B. Li** and T. Alstrøm, "On uncertainty estimation in active learning for image segmentation," in Proceedings of 2020 International Conference on Machine Learning: Workshop on Uncertainty and Robustness in Deep Learning, 2020.

Projects supervision

- 2021, Master thesis: Segmentation of cardiac structures based on MRI data using neural networks with analysis and evaluation of anatomical implausible segmentation errors (coding support), Katrine M. Ejlev and Michala Z. Blicher
- 2 2021, Project: *Unsupervised representation learning*, Till A. Aczel, Victor T. Olesen, Rasmus S. Mikkelsen, and David B. Ludvigsen
- 3 2022, Project: Federated machine learning, Asger L. Schultz, Søren W. Holm, and Gustav L. Moesmand
- 2023, Bachelor theis: *Explore representation learning in federated learning*, Victor T. Olesen, and Rasmus S. Mikkelsen

Skills and hobbies

Languages Native Chinese, Proficient English, Basic Dutch

Coding Python, PyTorch, R, Bash script, MATLAB, TensorFlow, Linux, AWS

Web Dev Basic level for React

Hobbies Yoga, read thriller books, hiking, sewing, and knitting

Awards

2016 – 2018 Danish Innovation Scholarship under DABAI

Referees

- 1. Associate Professor Tommy S. Alstrøm, Technical University of Denmark, ✓ tsal@dtu.dk
- 2. Associate Professor Mikkel N. Schmidt, Technical University of Denmark, 🖂 mnsc@dtu.dk